thebibleproject.com 2019-07-26

# Privacy Notice | The Bible Project

## The Bible Project

### Updated 29 June, 2017

**Introduction**

The Bible Project (the **“Bible Project”** or **“We”** ) respects your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy. This policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website jointhebibleproject.com or through our social media channels (our “Website”) and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information. This policy does not apply to information collected about you through any other means, including through non-electronic or offline means.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Website. By accessing or using this Website, you agree to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of this Website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.

This privacy notice is part of, and is governed by, the Bible Project Terms of Service. 

**Children Under the Age of 13**

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to or on the Website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Website or on or through any of its features. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at aeron@jointhebibleproject.com

**Information We Collect About You and How We Collect It**

We collect several types of information from and about users of our Website, including information:

  * by which you may be personally identified, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number (“personal information”); and/or about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Website and usage details.

We collect this information:

  * Directly from you when you provide it to us.
  * Automatically as you navigate through the site. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses, and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies.
  * From third parties, for example, third-party sites that use to log into our Website, such as Facebook or Twitter.

**Information You Provide to Us.**

The information we collect on or through our Website may include:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our Website, signing up for newsletters, posting material, or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our Website.
  * Records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact us.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfillment of your orders. You may be required to provide financial information before placing an order through our Website.

We use a third-party payment processor, Stripe, to handle payment transactions. You can read about Stripe’s privacy practices in the Stripe Privacy Policy.

You also may provide information to be published or displayed (hereinafter, “posted”) on public areas of the Website, or transmitted to other users of the Website or third parties (collectively, “User Contributions”). Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk. Although we limit access to certain pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. 

Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the Website with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.

**Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies.**

As you navigate through and interact with our Website, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns, including:

  * Details of your visits to our Website, including traffic data, location data, logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Website.
  * Information about your computer, device, and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system, device type, and browser type.
  * The information we collect automatically may include personal information or we may maintain it or associate it with personal information we collect in other ways or receive from third parties. It helps us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to:
  * Estimate our audience size and usage patterns.
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests.
  * Speed up your searches.
  * Recognize you when you return to our Website.

We (or service providers on our behalf) may use technologies, including “cookies” and “web beacons,” to automatically collect information from you when you use the Website. Cookies are small amounts of data that are stored within your Internet browser, which saves and recognizes your browsing habits. The Bible Project uses both session cookies (which track a user’s progression during one site visit) and persistent cookies (which track a user over time). Web beacons are web page elements that can recognize certain types of information on your computer or mobile device, such as the time and date you viewed a page, which emails are opened, which links are clicked, and similar information.

**“Do Not Track” Requests**

Your Internet browser and mobile device may allow you to adjust your browser settings so that “do not track” requests are sent to the websites you visit. The Bible Project does not respond to “do not track signals” at this time.

**How We Use Your Information**

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

  * To develop and improve our products and services.
  * To present our Website and its contents to you.
  * To provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us.
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.
  * To notify you about changes to our Website or any products or services we offer or provide though it.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Website.
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

The Bible Project also uses your personal information for contextual advertising. Contextual ads are customized based on the content you are viewing at any particular time. You can read more about this type of data-driven marketing on the Network Advertising Initiative website, [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

We may combine information we collect about you through the Services with other information about you that we receive from third-party sources. By way of example and not limitation, we may use a change of address or other list service to ensure that our records for your account are accurate.

**Disclosure of Your Information**

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction. 

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy:

  * To our subsidiaries and affiliates.
  * To contractors, payment processors, service providers, and other third parties we use to support our business.
  * To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of the Bible Project’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by the Bible Project about our Website users is among the assets transferred.
  * To our advertising and analytics partners, such as Google Analytics. The privacy policy of these third party companies applies to their collection, use and disclosure of your information. These third parties may combine your information with the information of other consumers for purposes of conducting these studies and/or analytics. For more information about Google Analytics, including how to opt out, please go to: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. For example, if you give us an email address to use the “email a friend” feature of our Website, we will transmit the contents of that email and your email address to the recipients.
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
  * With your consent.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * To comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
  * To enforce or apply our terms of use or terms of sale and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of the Bible Project, our customers, or others.

**Aggregate Information**

We may share aggregate or de-identified information without restriction. While this information will not identify you personally, in some instances third parties may be able to combine this aggregate information with other data they have about you, or that they receive from other third parties, in a manner that allows them to identify you personally.

**Accessing and Updating Your Information**

You may have the right to access the personal information we collect about you. You may also have the right to correct any errors contained in that information. For details, please email us at support@jointhebibleproject.com

**California Privacy Rights**

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice that identifies the categories of personal information we share with affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and provides contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address:

The Bible Project 501 SE 14th Avenue Portland, OR 97214

**Use of Information Outside Your Country of Residence**

The Website is directed to users located in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States and choose to use the Website or provide your information to us, you should be aware that we may transfer your information to the United States and process it there. The privacy laws in the United States may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. Your consent to this privacy policy followed by your submission of information to us through or in connection with the Website represents your agreement to the transfer of your information to the United States.

**Data Security**

We have implemented reasonable measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. 

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Website.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Website. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. If we decide to make a material change in this privacy policy, we will post it on this page. Your continued use of the Services after the posting of changes to this privacy policy will mean you accept these changes. In some cases, we may attempt to contact you through an email or other address you have provided, so we can give you choices about our using your information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection. If we make any material changes in our privacy practices that affect your personally identifiable information that is already in our possession, we will apply those changes to that older information only with your consent or as otherwise allowed by law. 

**Contact Information**

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at: The Bible Project 501 SE 14th Avenue Portland, OR 97214
